# **NEELAY PATEL**

Vaughan, ON L4H 4N2 | (647) 571-7280 | Neelaypatel10@gmail.com

# Objective

As an IT professional with 2+ years of experience, I have had many opportunities to work with a variety of hardware, software, and networking components. My technical proficiency which includes years of knowledge and understanding with repairing, troubleshooting in Windows and MAC operating systems. In addition, I also have experience in software development with a high proficiency in Java, HTML and CSS. I am currently aspiring to secure an IT position with a dynamic company where I can apply my technical skills and experience, while contributing to the company and organization's success.

## Education

## **Bachelor of Arts | York University**

Major: Information Technology

**Minor:** Economics

Relevant Coursework: Web Development, Systems Analysis and Design, Designing User

Interfaces

## Technical Skills

- Programming Languages: Python, Java, HTML, CSS, SQL
- Foundational understanding of AWS Cloud and services
- Familiarity with AWS Identity and Access Management and Cloud shell interface
- Understanding of AWS EC2 interfaces with ability to launch and maintain
- Complete knowledge of deployment and management of infrastructures

# Courses/Certifications

## **AWS Certified Solutions Architect**

Designing and implementing scalable and secure cloud solutions. Possessing the coveted AWS Certified Solutions Architect credential, while bringing expertise in architecting robust and efficient AWS infrastructures. With a keen understanding of cloud computing best practices and excelling in optimizing performance, reducing costs, and ensuring the highest levels of security.

## **AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner**

Designing and implementing scalable and secure cloud solutions. Possessing the coveted AWS Certified Solutions Architect credential, while bringing expertise in architecting robust and efficient AWS infrastructures. With a keen understanding of cloud computing best practices and excelling in optimizing performance, reducing costs, and ensuring the highest levels of security.

## **LinkedIn Learning Courses**

Learning Python, Database Foundations, Intro to DevOps, Project Management Foundations

## **Experience**

## **Technical Support Analyst**

September 2022 – Present | Musa Suleman Management Consultants

During the span of this job, I was responsible for providing tech support and assistance to users experiencing hardware, software, or networking issues. With a high technical understanding in Windows OS, MAC OS and Linux OS. I was required to diagnose problems, perform repairs, and apply updates to any devices running in the office.

#### Tech Intern

April 2022 – August 2022 | GaoTek Inc.

During the span of this job, I would help in troubleshooting software and hardware problems. Diagnosing, updating, and resolving any issues with current software applications. I would engage in digital marketing and SEO. While participating and collaborating with seniors in a virtual team environment.

## **Data Support Consultant Intern**

May 2021 – December 2021 | Musa Suleman Management Consultants

During the span of this job, I would help in troubleshooting software and hardware problems. Diagnosing, updating, and resolving any issues with current software applications. I would engage in digital marketing and SEO. While participating and collaborating with seniors in a virtual team environment.

# **Projects**

# Website Designer

May 2022 - Present | Freelance

Meeting and planning with clients to understand their needs and objectives for their website. Researching current data statistics to understand how to best reach targeted audiences and attract clients. Designing to help any visitors understand client portfolios and easily browse through business information. Maintaining and updating websites as needed.

## **Technical Writer**

September 2021 – December 2021 | iFixit.com

Researched, designed, and created Standard Operating Procedures (SOP) for repairs to laptops and phones. Creating visual aids to help users easily navigate and through their repair process. Organizing and presenting in a clear and concise manner to help understand. Total outreach for SOPs has reached over 2,500 people.

## **Leadership Workshops**

September 2015 – June 2017 | West Humber C.I.

During the span of these workshops, I acquired many leadership skills and qualities. Understood many key effective communication, management, and problem-solving qualities. Transitioned into a leader and passed on my skills and qualities to newer members of these workshops. Helped participants develop leadership skills and strategies that are applicable to the real world and business environments.

## Additional Information

Certifications: Digital Marketing, Technical Support, CPR and AED

Languages: English, Gujarati, Hindi, Punjabi